Hello everyone and
welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco. Hi guys,
my name is Catherine and today
we're talking about something
that is a little bit private.
That's right but very necessary to learn
in English because it's very very useful.
That's right so we're
talking about clothing
more specifically
underwear so the clothes you
wear under your
clothes. That's right.
Okay so let's just
jump into the dialogue.
Let's see what happens
today and we'll be back in a bit.
Look, I found a pair of men's boxers in
the laundry machine this morning. What?
That's weird. You're boyfriend.
Nah, Kevin only wears briefs.
Plus this pair is extra small.
What do they look like? They're
light blue with thin pink stripes.
Oh and there's a snoopie
on it which is hilarious.
Those are my undies. All right
so a lot of great vocab there.
Let's take a look at that now on
language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the first thing we have
here in language takeaway
is actually very interesting
Marco because we don't
say one underwear or
one boxers. We say a pair
of just like pants. A pair of
pants or a pair of underwear.
A pair of pants.
A pair of shorts.
The same thing goes for
underwear so I really don't
know why because it's
one piece. So are pants but
basically you have two
holes, two places for your legs.
So anything with your legs.
Your socks, your shoes,
your pants, your underwear.
You need a pair. You need
a pair because you've got the
both sides left and
right. All right so you got
a pair of men's boxers.
Now before we describe
the underwear part let's take
a look at this other machine.
A laundry machine. Okay so you know what
a machine is. It's usually something that
uses electricity to help
us with a task or a job.
But a laundry machine
is special because it helps
us clean our laundry. What
kind of things are laundry?
So anything that's your clothes.
So basically it's also
called a washing machine.
So laundry machine or
washing machine. Same thing.
It uses water and soap
to wash your clothes.
That's right. Okay so
now let's get into the
type of underwear
here specifically for men.
Usually we have
boxers, boxers shorts.
That's right so shorts means
that they're not long, they're short.
But boxers or boxer shorts as you say
are usually pretty loose. They're not very
tight and they're longer
than the other kinds of
underwear we have. Okay
so boxers are a type of
underwear that men wear
under their clothes and
as you say they're
pretty much shorts.
But they're called boxers or
you can call them boxer shorts.
Now the I guess the
classic or the common
form of men's underwear
are called briefs. Briefs.
Now these are smaller than
boxers and they're tighter.
Okay and they are usually made out
of some kind of material that stretches.
You can pull them a little
bit. And this is again a smaller
version, well a smaller
kind of underwear.
That's right. So boxers
are more like shorts.
Briefs are kind of and
briefs are not really short.
They're more like a, I guess
kind of like a swimming
suit they look like.
Yeah like a bathing suit
bottom for men.
Okay now that's it right.
Okay and these. Okay so
both of these things we could
actually describe as
undies. That's right so
undies is a common spoken
language way of saying underwear.
Okay so it's very
casual and it's
usually something that we
say with our family or friends.
Especially moms like
to say this with their kids.
Undies. All right
honey I'm going to buy
you some new undies
this week. Okay as a child
you feel very embarrassed.
Undies is a way to say underwear.
All right. Okay so that's all the vocab
that we have for you on language.
Take away why don't we
listen to our dialogue again and
we'll be back in a bit
with fluency builder.
Apparently I found a pair of men's boxers
in the laundry machine this morning. What?
That's weird. You're boyfriend.
Nah Kevin only wears briefs.
Plus this pair is extra small.
What do they look like? They're
light blue with thin pink stripes.
Oh and there's a snoopie
on it which is hilarious.
Those are my undies.
All right we're back so
now let's take a look at some descriptive
words in fluency builder. Fluency builder.
All right so as you said Marco
we have a lot of great phrases
today and some words for
describing underwear and
you can describe other
things with these words as well.
The first one we have
is a phrase extra small.
Okay so when you
buy underwear the sizes
you sometimes get small
extra small large medium
but it's just a way of
describing how big it is.
Right so you know the
S, the M and the L are
small medium on large
but if you see the X,
S that's extra small it
means it's very small.
All right we also have X
out which is extra large.
That's right. Okay so
now that we've described
the size now we're going
to describe a little bit
of how they look like
the colors and maybe any
characteristics. So the
first thing that we see is
the color is light blue. Okay so
we've got blue which is normal blue.
We have light
blue which is maybe
the color of the sky on
a beautiful summer day.
There's also we didn't
hear it in today's dialogue
but there's another color it's dark blue
which is almost more like purple or black.
That's right so this is the
way of describing a color.
Now it can be for any color
except white you don't really
say light white or dark
white. Yeah you don't.
So you could say light
green, dark green, light orange,
dark orange. Okay and
now some characteristics
they had some thin pink
stripes so we have the word
here thin. So not fat thin.
Pink we have the color
but what are stripes?
Okay stripes are a very
common design for clothes
and you often see stripes.
They're like lines. Okay
and so that means that
you have different
lines that are pink.
You often see stripes on flags.
So for example the American
flag has red and white
stripes. Okay very good
so as you said they're
lines and yeah usually in
clothing you can find
maybe shirts they have vertical
stripes or sometimes
even horizontal stripes.
Yes but these undies
are quite unique.
They're very special because
they have pink stripes.
That's right. Okay so
that's all the language
we have for you. Why
don't we listen to our
dialogue one last time and
we'll be back in a little bit.
Lately I found a pair of men's boxers
in the laundry machine this morning.
What? That's weird.
You're boyfriend.
Now Kevin only wears briefs.
Plus this pair is extra small.
What do they look like? They're
light blue with thin pink stripes.
Oh and there's a
Snoopy on it which
is hilarious. There's my
undies. All right so in
this case we're talking
about men's boxers shorts
because there was a confusion about the
boyfriend but women also wear boxers shorts.
It's very popular now among
women. Yeah it is it's usually
something that women
wear over their underwear.
Women don't really wear
boxer shorts as underwear.
Women's underwear is
smaller. It's like men's briefs.
Okay so if a girl
wears boxers and it's
usually for maybe if
they're just around the house
and you don't want to
wear pants and you don't
want to wear shorts you
can just wear a pair of
comfortable boxer shorts.
Exactly like they wear pajamas.
Okay and actually I think a lot of girls
also use boxer shorts as pajamas right?
That's right. They're
comfortable and they're light and
you know they're they're
they're usually made
from cotton which is a
nice material to sleep in.
Now when we're talking
about briefs there is
also another way that
I've heard that they're
called sometimes a
more maybe funny way of
calling them that some people
say they're called tidy wides.
That's right this is usually something
we say to joke because in America at least
many men like to wear
young men like to wear boxers.
Right. So they call
briefs tidy wides because
usually their briefs are
just white. They're plain.
They don't have any
design or any other color.
Now they're plain and they're white usually
or gray and they're tight not like boxers.
So the the casual name
this is not something
you want to say to
your English teacher.
The casual name where
the funny name is tidy
wides, tidy wides. And
actually this is a very
interesting because with
newer generations I think
men are wearing boxers
instead of briefs before
I think the only option
was briefs. Exactly.
But now boxers have grown
more more popular and
I think when you're a
little kid your mom always
buys you little briefs
and everything but then
when you're a teenager I think
you just switch over to boxers.
It's not as cool anymore to wear
briefs. I think it's
the whole fact of how
kids sometimes dress
with saggy or baggy pants
and so they like to show
their boxers underneath
for some reason. I
don't really understand it.
But if you do let us know
our website is EnglishPod.
com. We're going to
have all the vocabulary
and stuff on the website so check it out.
Alright we'll see you guys there. Bye.
[BLANK_AUDIO]